Yuzhou Xu

Software Engineer at Microsoft

Summary

My specialties include:

Programming: Python, Ruby, Java, C/C++, Date structure, Algorithms, Object-oriented Analysis and Design,

Design pattern

Web Framework & Server: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, ES2015, ¡Query, Ajax, JSON, React, HTML, CSS, Sass,

Bootstrap, Rest API, RSpec

Web Server: Apache, Nginx, Phusion Passenger

Database: MySQL, Slave replication, SQL

System: Unix/Linux, Puppet, Chef

Cloud: Amazon Web Service(EC2, EBS, and VPC), RightScale

OS & Architecture: OS principle, CPU micro-architecture, computer architecture and organization

Experiences: Distributed system, Cache, Database Administration, Data Analyst, DevOps, Test-Driven

Development, Agile Web Development, embedded system, Android mobile development, network (TCP/IP),

git, Eclipse

My Career objective:

My passion has always been about using technology to make people and society better and creating and enhancing useful software and solving technical problems.

Now seeking a full-time position in software development where I could both contribute and learn

Experience

Software Engineer (Bing - AI) at Microsoft

December 2016 - Present

Build AI infrastructure and tools for machine learning / deep learning on compliant big data sets, including CPU / GPU cluster management, distributed deep learning jobs schedule, virtual machines and distributed file system, python, docker, Windows and Linux.

Software Engineer at GuideSpark

March 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 10 months)

Projects:

1. Develop employee communications web application with Ruby on Rails, MySQL, JavaScript, ES2015, jQuery, Ajax, JSON, React, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, Build RESTful API, RSpec, front-end and back-end.

- 2. Develop customer admin management web application with Ruby on Rails, MySQL, JavaScript, ES2015, jQuery, Ajax, JSON, React, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, Build RESTful API, RSpec, front-end and back-end.
- 3. Design Tiny URL web application to shorten long URL to random short URL and improve scalability and availability for distributed system using Java, cache, MySQL

Software Engineer at AppFolio

October 2013 - February 2015 (1 year 5 months)

Responsibility#Work in the operations team to build and operate the 24/7 infrastructure for AppFolio's innovative SaaS products. Be responsible for the architecture, build, design and maintenance of AppFolio's hosting, computing, networking, and storage infrastructure.

Projects:

1. Develop deployment and customer account management application with Ruby on Rails for efficiency and automation and data analysis

Platform and technology#CentOS, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, RSpec, Git

2. Develop automatic release deployment application with Ruby on Rails for ease-to-use and management and data analysis

Platform and technology#CentOS, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Git

- 3. Build and operate MySQL replication slave servers on AWS VPC Platform and technology#CentOS , AWS, MySQL(Percona), Puppet, Shell, Ruby, Git Responsibility#Create AWS EC2 instance and file system, configure network(VPC, VPN) and seciruty groups, develop and run puppet install packages and set up cron job, configure MySQL slave replication and manage EC2 instance and MySQL slave. Increase operation team's efficiency: free operation team from maintaining machines and reduce cost, improve server and capacity flexibility and slave database performance.
- 4. Manage AppFolio Websites infrastructure on EC2 using RightScale
 Platform and technology#CentOS, MySQL(Percona), Ruby, Nginx, Passenger, Chef, Bash Shell
 Responsibility#Develop scripts to improve and make it more automatically and reduce the noise and analyze data.
- 5. Developed AppFolio production MySQL administration tools to help reduce outages. Platform and technology#CentOS, MySQL(Percona), Percona Toolkit, Ruby, Nginx, Passenger, logicmonitor, Bash Shell

Responsibility#Develop scripts to manage daily operation work such MySQL long query and slow query report, analyze log for http request metrics,

Percona Training: Operating and Troubleshooting for MySQL, Los Angeles 2014.12.10-11

Software Engineer Intern at Motorola

July 2011 - October 2011 (4 months)

Develop android's contact application with java and eclipse under Linux according to requirements, learn the specialized software development process and version control tool Git

Education

Southeast University

Master's Degree, Computer Architecture, 2010 - 2013

Honors and Awards

The sixth place in the dancing group of robotics competition in Jiangsu province, Star in technology in the second science festival at school, The champion of robotics competition at school

Yuzhou Xu

Software Engineer at Microsoft



Contact Yuzhou on LinkedIn